<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-02-18T23:06:21-02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">20k Budget</title><subtitle>My name is Fabricio Zuardi and this is the diary of my journey into developing a low-budget indie game.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Time tracking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/18/timesheet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Time tracking" /><published>2017-02-18T00:00:00-02:00</published><updated>2017-02-18T00:00:00-02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/18/timesheet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/18/timesheet.html">&lt;p&gt;I am on a quest to figure out if it is possible to make money with
a low budget independent game, among &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.20kbudget.com/2017/02/16/the-bet.html&quot;&gt;other things&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to monitor how well I am doing, to give feedback and transparency
to any potential &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.20kbudget.com/2017/02/17/crowdsale.html&amp;lt;Paste&amp;gt;&quot;&gt;investors&lt;/a&gt; and even for my own control
of where and how fast I am spending the arbitrary budget
of 20k dolllars that I have set, I need to somehow log all my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/20kbudget/expenses&quot;&gt;expenses&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if I hire an illustrator, a writer, a developer or some other kind of
artist, my plan is to document that cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, I haven’t raised funds yet, and the only person
that I know available to work without compensation for me is myself :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s not really true as well, because I will be investing my
time in this one-person-team, so I figure I must do something that I
really dislike, and that is filling up &lt;strong&gt;fucking timesheets&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That way I will be able to pay myself eventually, which is nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I will be testing a couple of options this weekend, I think I prefer
CLI and simple ones, although I have used web based ones in the past 
and they are quite OK as well (&lt;a href=&quot;https://toggl.com/&quot;&gt;toggl&lt;/a&gt; comes to mind). But nothing super fancy,
I will just pick any half-decent one (maybe &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/samg/timetrap&quot;&gt;timetrap&lt;/a&gt;) and get this out of my way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">I am on a quest to figure out if it is possible to make money with
a low budget independent game, among other things.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Raising funds: what is a Crowdsale?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/17/crowdsale.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Raising funds: what is a Crowdsale?" /><published>2017-02-17T00:00:00-02:00</published><updated>2017-02-17T00:00:00-02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/17/crowdsale</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/17/crowdsale.html">&lt;p&gt;Projects demands resources, and funding is always a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the available options for an indie developer or an indie development studio to raise money for a project, we have some
options that are quite common and well tested, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sell the car&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;burn of personal economies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;get a loan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;work for a company (and develop the project on your free time)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ask for donations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;apply for a grant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;start a crowdfunding campaing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;start a company and sell securities of it in a highly regulated market, with different rules on each country&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there is another one, that is quite popular in the crypto-currencies space:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sell digital assets (tokens) representing some reward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last option is the one I am most interested in, since the issuance of tokens is simple and it is flexible enough
for different kinds of arrangements. They can be used to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pay dividends for the token-holders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;give refunds on failure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;give token-holders voting rights&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;represent some phisical reward&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;represent ownership in the project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;be traded in the free market, or used as currency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically you have enough flexibility to come up with any set of your own crazy rules, and even write software to enforce
some of your made-up rules if you are inclined to go on that path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People use the terms &lt;strong&gt;crowdsale&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;ICO&lt;/strong&gt; (initial coin offer), or &lt;strong&gt;equity crowdsale&lt;/strong&gt; to describe those digital
assets sales and differentiate it from traditional equity crowdfunding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are different platforms, blockchains and protocols available for doing a crowdsale,
some of them are built on top of Bitcoin, some on top of Ethereum and others. The Bitcoin network is the most 
secure because of proof of work and adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Projects demands resources, and funding is always a challenge.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Bet</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/16/the-bet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Bet" /><published>2017-02-16T00:00:00-02:00</published><updated>2017-02-16T00:00:00-02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/16/the-bet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/16/the-bet.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;main-question&quot;&gt;Main question:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can a good indie game be written on a shoestring budget?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;secondary-questions&quot;&gt;Secondary questions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can a project based on openness, transparency and free licences make money to it’s investors?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is it possible to make a commercially successful mobile app with a budget of under 20k dollars?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How difficult would it be to raise money for developing such an app?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What kind of team would be necessary?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do I have the skills to lead this effort and make it happen?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the challenge, the experiment, the journey I am starting today.
I want to figure out how far can a project that challenges stablished business models go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly likely I will fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you want to follow my exploration and discoveries please stick around.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Main question:</summary></entry></feed>
